Hey everyone, my name is Jeremiah
Kowski. Thanks for listening to the Grow
Your Life podcast. If you're a coach,
mentor, trainer, and you want to know,
how do I get more clients, make more
money on the internet? I'm going to show
you how to do that. In this podcast, I
walk you through that process. Now, I
want to talk about something I was
talking about with my coaching group,
the Wealthy Coach Academy, which by the
way, if you've not seen this or heard
about it, I work with mentors, coaches,
and trainers every single week to help
them scale their businesses, make more
money than they ever thought was
possible with their marketing and sales
strategy, and I come alongside you and
walk you through that entire process
start to finish. I'd love to see you in
there, and I'd love to work with you to
help you reach six and even seven
figures in there. One of the biggest
issues that people have is that they
overplan themselves and they don't
execute. They don't take action. They
come up with an idea, they come up with
multiple ideas. And I've been guilty of
this myself where I had a bunch of great
ideas and stuff that I wanted to do in
my business, but I didn't actually go
out there and take action on it. And I
find that often times this actually has
a lot more to do with dopamine than
anything else. We end up becoming
addicted to the process of planning,
coming up with ideas, coming up with a
good idea. And it's actually proven that
our brain is wired in anticipation.
Anything that we're
anticipating, we end up loving and
enjoying and getting pleasure from more
than actually doing it. Because if we
actually took action, we have to come
face to face with the fact that, okay,
what if it fails? What if it doesn't
work out? what if things don't go how I
wanted them to? And that becomes painful
for us. And so, you got to become aware
of the fact that your brain does this
and that if you're a mentor or coach and
you're wanting to launch a course or a
coaching program, you're struggling to
actually get stuff out there to actually
get stuff launched that a part of it
might be because you're not aware that
this is going on and you're just you
just feel like you're fighting it and
striving past it. So, one of the things
that I like to do is this. I like to
say, "Okay, let
me I'm still going to enjoy the
planning. I'm still going to enjoy for
me it's learning. Um, but I also need to
take action. I need to take action on at
least two things before I learn a new
thing or before I plan a new
thing." And what this will do is this
will start to rewire that part of your
brain to where you start to enjoy taking
action, where you actually derive
pleasure out of taking action versus
just the anticipation of it. So, I want
you to become aware of this pattern in
your life. Everything that you've ever
wanted in your business is directly
connected to your ability to execute and
take action on the ideas that you have.
The number one thing that stops people,
again, perfectionism is a big part about
it, but it goes beyond just
perfectionism. We've been we've talked
about that for the longest time.
Perfectionism. We can't let that stop us
from doing the things that we want to
do. But let's say maybe you're not
dealing with perfectionism. It just
doesn't feel right and you're you're
especially somebody who's intuitive and
you're waiting until something feels
right. Well, here's where sometimes we
get deceived a little bit by our
internal chemicals and hormones.
Dopamine, the different chemical
messengers inside of our brains that
tell us certain messages. And so we feel
like, oh, it's going to be painful. It's
a bad thing to take action. Our brain is
subconsciously believing this
message. And I'm saying this as somebody
who literally has dealt with this on a
very deep level and it's affected my
ability to be able to reach my goals
until I became aware of it. And I
started to unravel what can I do to
change this. So, one of the ways that I
actually did was I would go into chat
GPT and the new version of chat GPT 03
or above 03 is great.
Um, I would explain what I'm dealing
with. Hey, I'm struggling to take
action. I have this here. Explain to me
what's going on on a psychological
level, on a chemical level. um and help
me understand and then what are some
practical aspects and things that I can
do to help me start to take action more
rather than sitting around and doing
stuff. And what I found was there's a
couple of things. Number one, the reason
why we struggle to take action, there's
a great book that I read that I
recommend that anybody reads called
Indistractible. I really actually need
to read it again. Um because it's just
to remind myself, it's been a couple
years of just the topic of it. But
Indestructible right here, incredible
book. And the the topic that
Indistractible is about is about what
controls our attention and how to take
it back. And one of the number one
issues is that the reason why we get
distracted or pulled away from things is
because we're avoiding the potential
pain that we experience if we stayed
focused. If we actually did the work
that we said that we're setting out to
do and and then it dives deeper into
what you can do to become more
indistractible in your life. Uh, I
bought this book during COVID when
everything was distracting all of us.
And it's been about 5 years since I've
read it, but I still think back to it
all the time when it comes to this
topic. If you
can start to pinpoint,
okay, what are the triggers inside of
me? What is the pain? What are the
fears? What are the
underlying? And by the
way, you're not just going to answer it
right now while you're listening to this
podcast.
It's it's usually going to be something
that's deeper. That is going to be your
your your brain. For those of you who
who want to understand this side of
things, your brain actually hides it
from you. It hides the actual real
reason why we're doing this from us. Um,
it's a self-protective mechanism that is
actually happening in our brains that
does this that it keeps us safe by
not revealing to us why the root cause
of certain things happen. But many times
it can go back to an experience that
we're trying to avoid or something that
we saw happen to somebody else that we
don't want to happen. You know, listen,
if you get stung by a bee, you're not
going to get stick your hand into a
beehive. If you get burnt on a hot
stove, you're not going to touch that
hot stove again. And it's the exact same
way when it comes to our businesses. And
yet, it's usually like three or four
layers deep as to why we're actually
doing that. And and that's where it kind
of becomes a bit of a challenge to
really
identify, okay, why am I doing this? Why
is my why are my actions following this?
Why am I so strongly avoiding this
thing? Why am I not doing the thing that
I need to do? And I can look at my life.
Listen, I got things I I have been
procrastinating for an entire
week on something that I need to do,
something that I need to submit in my my
business, in my life that I need to get
done. I have something else I've been
procrastinating for an entire
month that I've not done. And I can look
at it and it's like, well, you know
what? What if it doesn't work out? What
if it's harder than I thought it would
be? What if what if there's details that
I don't want to know right yet because
they're going to cost me more time or
money? And so all of these things, gosh,
it's it's it's overwhelming, right? It's
overwhelming because we don't want to
look at those things. And that's what
it's it's it's less painful to
procrastinate and not do the thing than
to just simply do it. And internally it
starts to feel like like we start to get
nauseous even and and a headache and we
start to
feel and that's often times when we
decide to go do something else to
distract ourselves from that pain that
internalized
pain. And
so listen, I'm not perfect in this. I
promise you that.
Um, but I have learned at least the
first step is to become aware that it's
happening. To become aware that you're
doing this, to become aware that it's
going on. We all do this. We're humans.
It's how humans operate. We're not
robots. Thank
God. And yet often times we don't know
why this stuff is happening. And just by
becoming aware of it, just by sitting
and saying, "Okay, what am I feeling
right now when I think about going to do
that thing? When I think about doing
that thing, what feels so difficult?"
And again, often it could literally just
be you start to feel a nausea inside of
you. Maybe you don't want to be judged
or scrutinized or something like that or
there's some other underlying issue. We
all have different ones. They're all
different
reasons. And yet, at the end of the day,
this right here is one of the number one
reasons why we don't take action on the
stuff that we've set out to do in our
lives and in our
business. Simply because we're playing
this waiting game. We're playing this,
well, I'll do it next time game. The
time is now to take action. If not now,
when? And that will change everything
for you, having that perspective.
Listen, I'd love for you to not wait and
delay on joining my Wealthy Coach
Academy program. I know maybe you've
been hearing about it. you've been
putting it off for a long time, take
action. Jump in, register for one of our
trainings where we talk about it. You
can go check one out in the description
below and I'd love to have you be a part
of it. Just try it out for 14 days and
see if it's for you. See you in there.
We'll talk soon.
[Applause]
[Music]